totaltools.com.au 2018-05-09

# Total Tools Privacy Policy | Total Tools

**PRIVACY POLICY**

_Total Tools Importing Pty Ltd ABN 18 084 220 342 and its related entities as defined in the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth) (“Total Tools”) ** ** respect the privacy of individuals and treat your Personal Information with respect and integrity. This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) sets out the way in which Total Tools collects and handles your Personal Information and complies with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). Total Tools reserves the right to amend, at its sole discretion, this Privacy Policy without notice._ ****

**1.**   **Collection of Personal Information**

1.1       Generally you can deal with Total Tools anonymously (i.e. without identifying yourself). However, by doing any of the following you consent to the collection of your Personal Information by Total Tools in accordance with this Privacy Policy:

(a)        Visit Total Tools’ website and providing your Personal Information;

(b)        Interact or follow social media managed by Total Tools (such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube or Instagram);

(c)        Place an order via a store, telephone or website;

(d)        Apply for a job with Total Tools;

(e)        Submit website feedback, enquires or comments;

(f)         Provide your Personal Information for the provision of special offers by Total Tools or any other service provided by Total Tools, including the newsletter;

(g)        Enter into an agreement with Total Tools; or

(h)        Any other method of collection as determined by Total Tools from time to time.

1.2       Total Tools may collect and hold the following personal information (“Personal Information”):

(a)        Name, address, phone and/or facsimile number and email address;

(b)        Australian Company Number and/or Australian Business Number (if required);

(c)        Details of your orders;

(d)        IP address;

(e)        Loyalty program, award or redemption details;

(f)         Bank details; and

(g)        Any additional information provided to Total Tools, including any feedback, rating or comments made by you.

**2\. Use of Personal Information**

2.1       Total Tools uses the Personal Information for the purpose for which it was specified or reasonably apparent at the time when the Personal Information was collected. The Personal Information may be used in respect to the following:

(a)        Providing order confirmations;

(b)        Processing and delivering of orders;

(c)        Assisting the offering of products and services by Total Tools or its related entities, merchants, contractors, agents and/or employees;

(d)        Processing of job or franchise applications and the provision of relevant information in this respect;

(e)        Communicating promotional offers, marketing information or special events;

(f)         Responding to feedback, ratings, comments, complaints and enquiries; and

(g)        Using for administrative, marketing, planning, employment performance review, service or product development purposes.

2.2       You may advise Total Tools if you do not wish to receive any promotional offers, marketing information or special events from Total Tools.

**3\. Disclosure of Personal Information**

3.1       Where appropriate and required, Total Tools may disclose your Personal Information:

(a)        To other associated Total Tools entities, including its delivery company;

(b)        To Total Tools’ suppliers, agents or contractors in connection with or for the purpose of Total Tools’ business;

(c)        Where the law requires or authorises Total Tools to do so; and

(d)        To any other third party notified by you at the time of or after collecting your Personal Information, including the merchant performing services to you.

3.2       Total Tools will not disclose Personal Information to overseas recipients.

**4\. Access to and Protection of Personal Information**

4.1       Subject to the  _Privacy Act 1988  _(Cth), Total Tools provides you with access to your Personal Information upon your request.

4.2       Total Tools will take reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Information is accurate, up to date and complete. However, Total Tools relies on you advising of any changes or inaccuracies of your Personal Information. Please advise Total Tools if you are of the view that any of your Personal Information requires updating or correcting.

4.3       Total Tools will take reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information from misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure (other than set out in the Privacy Policy).

4.4       No data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while Total Tools strives to protect your Personal Information, Total Tools cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Total Tools over the internet, and you do so at your own risk. Once Total Tools receives your transmission, Total Tools makes its best effort to try and ensure the information and Personal Information security both on Total Tools systems and while in transit between Total Tools’ systems and the companies who provide Total Tools with the various systems.

**5\. Complaints Procedure**

5.1       If you wish to make a complaint about a breach of the Privacy Policy or the  _Privacy Act 1988  _(Cth) by Total Tools, please lodge a complaint to the Total Tools privacy policy co-ordinator (“Co-ordinator”) at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) The Co-ordinator will investigate your complaint and determine how it can be resolved.

5.2       Should you not be satisfied with the way your complaint was handled or determined, you may contact Total Tools or, alternatively, contact the Australian Information Commissioner via [www.oaic.gov.au](https://www.oaic.gov.au/).
